War is hell. This was worse...
Platoon Leader is a drama, war, action film directed by Aaron Norris.
West Point graduate lieutenant Jeff Knight meets cynicism when taking command of
sergeant Michael McNamara's tour veterans platoon in a Vietnamese trench camp.
Unlike his predecessor, who hid till the end of his tour, Jeff takes charge,
experiences the manual doesn't allow coping with all realities and gets wounded.
He returns, now fully respect by men and superiors.
Besides the Vietcong, the platoon wrestles with the inscrutable villagers, which the G.I.'s officially protect, but also
fear as some collaborate with them, other covertly with the Cong, either way subject to bloody reprisals.
Lt. Jeff Knight, played by Michael Dudikoff.
Sgt. Michael McNamara, played by Robert F. Lyons.
Raymond Bacera, played by Michael DeLorenzo.
Joshua Parker, played by Jesse Dabson.
Sgt. Robert Hayes, played by Rick Fitts.
Jan Shultz, played by Tony Pierce.
Platoon Leader is a 1988 war film set in the Vietnam War and directed by Aaron Norris (Chuck Norris's brother; this is his only film
without his brother in the cast); it stars Michael Dudikoff and Michael DeLorenzo and was filmed in South Africa.
It is loosely based on James R.
McDonough's memoir of the same name.
The film is about a newly commissioned infantry lieutenant who
arrives in Vietnam to take over his first platoon.
He finds he has to prove himself and earn the trust of
the enlisted men if he is to lead them.
The film explores themes of vietnam war, vietnam, vietcong, us army.
The tone is emotional.